Guide to the Julia Driver Collection of Women in Photography
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
- Card Photographs and Other Photographic Materials, 1845-1940; Series II; 5.83
  - Photographic Materials
    - Wallgren, Therése, circa 1895; (1 carte-de-visite) (Box 14, Folder 529)
      Active in Berga, Borgholm, Högsby, Mönsterås, and Oskarshamn, Sweden, circa 1885-1910
    - Wallis, Mary, Mrs., circa 1885; (1 cabinet photograph) (Box 14, Folder 530)
      Active in Glenwood, Iowa, circa 1885
      Also known as Mrs. Charles W. Wallis
    - Walter, Jennie, circa 1895; (1 cabinet photograph) (Box 14, Folder 531)
      Active in Corunna, Michigan, circa 1895
    - Ward, Susan, Mrs. (born circa 1838), 1882-1889; (5 cartes-de-visite) (Box 14, Folder 532)
      Active in Croydon, England, 1882-1889
      Also known as Mrs. H. Ward or Mrs. Henry Ward
      Includes a portrait of Ellen Knight Chandler, wife of Henry Chandler
    - Ward, W. Blanch, circa 1890; (1 cabinet photograph) (Box 14, Folder 533)
      Active in Richmond, Indiana, circa 1890
      Also known as Chicago Art Gallery
    - Warner, Birdia E., Miss (born 1859), circa 1892; (1 cabinet photograph) (Box 14, Folder 534)
      Active in Ottumwa and Brighton, Iowa, circa 1892
      Also known as Miss B. E. Warner
    - Watts, Cassie V., Mrs. (born 1877), circa 1900; (1 card photograph) (Box 14, Folder 535)
      Active in McPherson, Kansas, circa 1900
      Also known as Mrs. C. V. Watts
    - Weale, Marie, Miss, circa 1899-1902; (1 cabinet photograph) (Box 14, Folder 536)
      Active in Nuneaton and London, England, circa 1899-1902
      Also known as Helios Studio
    - Weems, Sarah A., Mrs. (born 1867), circa 1900; (1 photographic print) (Box 14, Folder 537)
      Active in Baxter, Iowa, circa 1900
    - Weigel, Mary, Miss (1858-1934), circa 1895; (1 cabinet photograph) (Box 14, Folder 538)
      Active in Dyersville, Iowa, 1882-1918
    - Weikert, Mabel Strikler, Mrs. (born 1863), circa 1900; (1 cabinet photograph and 1 imperial photograph) (Box 14, Folder 539)
      Active in Norton, Kansas, circa 1900
      Also known as Mrs. W. M. Weikert or Mrs. William M. Weikert
      Includes a portrait of two women with very long hair posed standing
    - Weisler, M., Mrs., circa 1910; (1 photographic postcard) (Box 14, Folder 540)
      Active in Coney Island, New York, circa 1910
    - Weld, Matilda Coward, Mrs. (born circa 1837), circa 1870; (1 carte-de-visite) (Box 14, Folder 541)
      Active in Penn Yan, New York, circa 1870
      Also known as Mrs. Jas. A. Weld, Mrs. James Albert Weld, Mrs. Matilda Cayward Weld, or Mrs. Willard A. Hill
    - Wells, Catherine J., Mrs. (born circa 1827), 1860-1867; (3 cartes-de-visite) (Box 14, Folder 542)
      Active in Coldwater, Michigan, as well as Radnor, Ohio, 1860-1867
      Also known as Mrs. C. J. Wells
    - Wells, Eliza Ann, Miss (born circa 1843), circa 1865; (1 carte-de-visite) (Box 14, Folder 543)
      Active in Hull, England, circa 1865
      Also known as Mr. & Miss Wells
    - Westbrook, Sallie M., Mrs. (1862-1932), circa 1899-1900; (2 cabinet photographs) (Box 14, Folder 544)
      Active in Chickasha, Oklahoma, as well as Belcherville, Texas, 1896-1901
      Also known as Mrs. S. M. Westbrook, Mrs. Sarah M. Westbrook, or Mrs. William Westbrook
      Includes a portrait of Wilma Cloud (born 1898), in March 1899
    - Wetterberg, Lisa, circa 1900; (1 carte-de-visite) (Box 14, Folder 545)
      Active in Gävle, Sweden, circa 1900
    - White & Hubbell, Misses, circa 1885; (2 cabinet photographs) (Box 14, Folder 546)
      Active in San Jose, California, circa 1885
    - Widgrén, Julia Viktorina Rosalie, (1842-1917), circa 1885; (1 carte-de-visite) (Box 14, Folder 547)
      Active in Vaasa, Finland, 1866-1890
    - Wigand, Ottilie, circa 1875; (1 carte-de-visite and 1 cabinet photograph) (Box 14, Folder 548)
      Active in Wiesbaden, Germany, circa 1870-1900
    - Wightman, Maggie, Mrs. (born 1864), circa 1890; (1 cabinet photograph) (Box 14, Folder 549)
      Active in Colton, California, circa 1890
      Also known as Mrs. E. P. Wightman or Mrs. Edgar Pettis Wightman
    - Wikström, Agnes, circa 1880-1890; (1 carte-de-visite) (Box 14, Folder 550)
      Active in Piteå, Sweden, circa 1880-1890
    - Wilkie, Sarah, Mrs. (born 1835), circa 1869; (1 carte-de-visite) (Box 14, Folder 551)
      Active in New York City, circa 1869-1890
      Also known as Mrs. J. Wilkie or Mrs. James Wilkie
    - Williams, H. R., Mrs., circa 1865-1875; (7 cartes-de-visite) (Box 15, Folder 552)
      Active in Bath, England, circa 1865-1875
      Includes a portrait of the Indian ayah (domestic servant) of the Doveton family
    - Williams, Sarah, Mrs. (born circa 1826), 1876-1900; (49 cartes-de-visite and 4 cabinet photographs) (Box 15, Folder 553)
      Active in Manchester and Wolverhampton, England, 1876-1900
      Also known as Mrs. Thomas Williams
      Includes a portrait of a man pruning a tree.
      - Cartes-de-visite from a single album, circa 1880 (Box 15, Folder 554)
    - Wilmarth, Hattie H., Mrs. (born circa 1841), 1877-1878; (1 cabinet photograph) (Box 15, Folder 555)
      Active in Chicago, Illinois, 1877-1878
      Also known as Mrs. H. H. Wilmarth
    - Wilson, Julia, Mrs. (born circa 1850), circa 1881-1887; (1 carte-de-visite) (Box 15, Folder 556)
      Active in Liverpool, England, circa 1881-1887
      Also known as Mrs. W. Wilson or Mrs. Walter Wilson
    - Wimermark, Pauline Nelson, Mrs. (born circa 1850), 1882-1884; (7 cabinet photographs) (Box 15, Folder 557)
      Active in Chicago and Cambridge, Illinois, 1882-1884
      Also known as Mrs. A. H. Wimermark, Mrs. Arvid H. Wimermark, or Wimermark & Carson
      Includes portraits of Carl Lindquist (born circa 1841)
    - Woodworth, Grace Adelle, Miss (1872-1967), circa 1898; (1 cabinet photograph) (Box 15, Folder 558)
      Active in Union Springs, New York, 1897-
      Also known as Miss. G. A. Woodworth
    - Woodworth, Ruby M. Thorp, Mrs. (1842-1922), circa 1864-1880; (10 cartes-de-visite and 1 cabinet photograph) (Box 15, Folder 559)
      Active in Geneva, Ohio, circa 1864-1880
      Also known as Miss R. M. Thorp, Mrs. J. P. Woodworth, or Mrs. James P. Woodworth
      Includes portraits of Ella C. Thompson (circa 1853-1874) and Ettie Edson (circa 1855-1870)
    - Worsfold, Misses, circa 1865; (1 carte-de-visite) (Box 15, Folder 560)
      Probably Sarah Worsfold (born circa 1850) and Elizabeth Worsfold (born circa 1851)
      Active in Waukegan, Illinois, circa 1865
    - Worthing, Hanna H., Miss (born 1843), 1867-1870; (15 cartes-de-visite) (Box 15, Folder 561)
      Active in New Bedford, Massachusetts, 1867-1870
      Also known as Mrs. Pardon DeVoll
      Includes a photograph by Smith & Andrews, the firm that succeeds her, as well as a portrait of a woman by John Adams Whipple (1822–1891) of Boston, Massachusetts, that accompanied a portrait by Worthing
    - Wright, Mary L., Mrs. (born 1837), circa 1880; (1 cabinet photograph) (Box 15, Folder 562)
      Active in Princeton, Indiana, 1880
      Also known as W. R. Wright & Wife or Mrs. William R. Wright
    - Wyatt, Mary Jane Sears, Mrs. (born 1840-1918), circa 1883-1890; (2 cartes-de-visite, 9 cabinet photographs, and 3 photographic prints) (Box 15, Folder 563)
      Active in Roseville, Illinois, as well as Wilcox, Holdrege, and Minden, Nebraska, circa 1872-1917
      Also known as Mrs. M. J. Wyatt or Mrs. Andrew Anderson Wyatt
      Includes a view of the tailor shop of August Sandahl in Holdrege, Nebraska, circa 1883, as well as discrete portraits of Alta L. Slawson Hammond (born 1870) and a woman posed playing a guitar.
    - Wykes, Julia Elmira Jones, Mrs. (circa 1840-1871), 1864 June; (1 carte-de-visite) (Box 15, Folder 564)
      Active in Grand Rapids, Michigan, circa 1863-1864
      Also known as Mrs. Elmira Wykes, Mrs. E. S. Wykes, or Mrs. Edward S. Wykes
      Includes a portrait of Price H. Bescott, June 1864
    - Yates Sisters, circa 1892; (3 cabinet photographs) (Box 15, Folder 565)
      Partnership between Lillian Yates (born 1867) and Margaret Yates (born 1873)
      Active in Waseca and Worthington, Minnesota, as well as Edgemont, South Dakota, 1888-1906
    - Young & Wife, circa 1880; (1 cabinet photograph) (Box 15, Folder 566)
    - Young, Sarah J., Mrs. (born 1848), circa 1900; (1 cabinet photograph) (Box 15, Folder 567)
      Active in Fayetteville, Arkansas, circa 1885-1900
      Also known as Mrs. S. J. Young
      Portrait of Ernest Weyer (born 1898)
  - Photographic Materials by Men
    This series consists of photographs created by male commercial photographers. Some of these photographers had partnerships or relationships with women photographers, while others possessed feminine names.
    - Bagge, Per (1866-1936), circa 1896-1903; (3 cartes-de-visite) (Box 15, Folder 568)
      Active in Lund and Skåne, Sweden, circa 1890-1836
      Successor to Lina Jonn in Lund, Sweden; he operated the studio under her name until 1903
    - Bayley & Cramer, 1865-1868; (1 carte-de-visite) (Box 15, Folder 569)
      Partnership between Wilbur Fisk Bayley (born circa 1840) and Charles Lake Cramer (1835-1911)
      Active in San Francisco, California, 1865-1868
    - Brandt, Alexis, circa 1897; (1 cabinet photograph) (Box 15, Folder 570)
      Active in Helsingborg, Malmö, and Stockholm, Sweden, circa 1890-1897
      Former partner of Lina Jonn in Helsingborg, Sweden, in 1890
    - Burno, L. (born circa 1848), 1882; (1 carte-de-visite) (Box 15, Folder 571)
      Also had a partnership with his brother, E. Bruno
      Active in Tekamah, Nebraska, circa 1882-1886
      Also known as E. & L. Burno
      Includes a portrait of Elsie E. Butts (born circa 1869) and probably her mother, Anna E. Butts (born circa 1837)
    - Collier & Boley, circa 1860-1870; (1 carte-de-visite) (Box 15, Folder 572)
      Partnership between Charles C. Boley (born circa 1835) and G. L. Collier (born circa 1843)
      Active in New Haven, Missouri, circa 1860-1870
    - Cornish, George Bancroft (1876-1946), circa 1910; (1 card photograph) (Box 15, Folder 573)
      Active in Arkansas City, Kansas, circa 1898-1937
      Former partner of William S. Prettyman (1858-1932), whose studio he acquired in 1905. Cornish employed Edith Berroth (1895-1989) as an assistant from 1912 and bequeathed his studio to her upon his death. She operated the studio until her retirement in 1969.
    - Dames, William White (born 1841)
      Active in San Francisco, California, circa 1871-1886, and Oakland, California, 1886-1904.
      Presumably assisted by his wife, Adelia C. Dames (born 1849). She also owned or co-owned several galleries, 1886-1904.
      - Dames & Butler, 1882-1885; (1 cabinet photograph) (Box 15, Folder 574)
        Partnership with Charles Albert Butler (1843-1924) in San Francisco, California, 1882-1885
        Portrait of Rose Glennon Palmer (born 1839), the wife of Robert Palmer (1823-1905), a miner and rancher in Kern, California
      - Dames & Hayes, 1877-1881; (1 cabinet photograph) (Box 15, Folder 575)
        Partnership with Henry C. Hayes (born circa 1842) in San Francisco, California
    - Edwards & Son, circa 1898; (1 cabinet photograph) (Box 15, Folder 576)
      Partnership between Jay Dearborn Edwards (1831-1900) and William M. Edwards (born 1864) in Atlanta, Georgia, 1888-1900. The elder Edwards worked as a photographer in St. Louis, Missouri, in 1857, as well as New Orleans, Louisiana, 1859-circa 1862
      Portrait of Kitty Van Dyke Anderson (born 1871), the wife of Clifford LeConte Anderson (1862-1933)
    - Erna, Atelier, circa 1900; (1 carte-de-visite) (Box 15, Folder 577)
      Photograph studio operated by A. Blankhorn, Arthur Marx, Wilhelm Husenbeth, and H. Bogler in Frankfurt, Germany, circa 1895-1905
      The carte-de-visite was probably created by Wilhelm Husenbeth
    - Fehrenbach, Emilian (circa 1818-1867), 1862; (1 carte-de-visite) (Box 15, Folder 578)
      Active in London, England, 1854-1867. Presumably assisted by his wife, Isabel Elisha Fehrenbach (1831-1877)
      Also known as German School of Photography
    - Hill, Edward (born circa 1841), circa 1871-1881; (3 cartes-de-visite) (Box 15, Folder 579)
      Active in Wolverhampton, England, circa 1871-1881; presumably assisted by his wife, Ann S. Hill (born circa 1847)
    - Long, C. B., and L. R. Scott, circa 1885; (1 cabinet photograph) (Box 15, Folder 580)
      Partnership between C. B. Long and L. R. Scott in Susanville, California, circa 1885
    - McCormick, Wales R. (born 1832), 1900; (1 cabinet photograph) (Box 15, Folder 581)
      Active in Canton, Missouri, and Quincy, Illinois, circa 1890-circa 1900. He was the brother of Candace McCormick Reed (1818-1900), who also operated a studio in Quincy, Illinois.
      Copy photograph portrait of Susanna Davidson Norman (1816-1866), circa 1865, the wife of Jabez Norman (1814-1863)
    - Olsen, Kristen, circa 1880; (1 carte-de-visite) (Box 15, Folder 582)
      Active in "Vigaardsheien", which is probably in Denmark, circa 1885
    - Pacault, Michel, circa 1875; (2 cartes-de-visite) (Box 15, Folder 583)
      Active in Pau, France, circa 1885
      Includes a view four men posed standing and reclining in front of a mountain peak in the Pyrenées
    - Rile, Harry Frantz (1860-1949), circa 1905; (1 carte-de-visite) (Box 15, Folder 584)
      Active in Santa Monica, California, 1887-circa 1908; presumably assisted by his wife, Georgetta May Heimer Rile (1874-1955)
      View of the Sawtelle Veterans Home at Santa Monica, California, Barracks No. 3 and 4
    - Robinson, J. B., circa 1900; (1 cabinet photograph) (Box 15, Folder 585)
      Active in Duluth, Minnesota as well as New York and Bonham, Texas, circa 1897-1900
      Also known as the Robinson Studio
      View of two men posed standing in front of the storefront for the insurance agency of Boyd and Bradford and attorney offices of William Amrose Bramlette (born 1855) in Bonham, Texas. One of the proprietors of the insurance agency, probably Nathaniel Comstock Bradford (1835-1935), is identified on the left
    - Ward, Alfred Thomas (1850-1903), 1891-1893; (1 cabinet photograph) (Box 15, Folder 586)
      Active in London, England, 1879-1903
      Portrait of two men dressed as tramps
    - Unidentified photographer, circa 1900; (1 photographic print) (Box 15, Folder 587)
      Portrait of a young girl posed standing and holding a flower, identified as Miriam Levy at two years old
  - Oversize Photographic Materials
    Photographic materials and printed matter with dimensions larger than 22 x 29 cm (8.7 x 11.4 in.)
    - Crawford, E., Mrs., 1853 January 17; (1 newspaper) (Box 16, Folder 588)
      Active in Newark, New Jersey, 1853
      Also known as Park Daguerreian Gallery
      Issue of the Newark Daily Advertiser, January 17, 1853, which contains an advertisement for Mrs. E. Crawford
    - Libby, Minnie F., Miss (1863-1947), 1940 December 2; (1 tear sheet) (Box 16, Folder 589)
      Portion of an article about Libby, "Speaking of Pictures.. ." in Life, December 2, 1940, 12-15.
    - Mayer-Landauer, Helga, circa 1935; (1 photographic print) (Box 16, Folder 590)
      Active in Berlin, Germany, circa 1935
      Possibly the actress Helga Mayer; she appeared in Der Stammbaum des Dr. Pistorius ( Dr. Pistorius' Family Tree, 1939)
      View of a woman flying a kite on a beach
    - Richards, Wynn, Mrs. (1888-1960), circa 1935; (1 photographic print) (Box 16, Folder 591)
      Active in New York City, circa 1918-1960
      Also known as Mrs. Martha Wynn Richards, Mrs. Dorsey Richards, or Mrs. George Herbert Taylor
      Portrait of a man wearing a tuxedo and holding a cigarette